Preliminary Inventory of the Alex Inkeles papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Becoming Modern: Individual Change in Six Developing Countries, (Harvard University Press, 1974) research materials, 1966-1974 (Box 536)
  - HUPSCAD India papers (Folder 548:)
    - Differential Impact of Factory Experience and Education on Caste, Ethics, and Religious Groups (Folder 548: 12)
    - The University and the Indian Society: The Case of Ranchi University (Folder 548: 13)
    - Modernization of India: Studies in Socio-Cultural Aspects (Folder 548: 14)
    - The Impact of Foreign Study: The Indian Experience (Folder 548: 15)
    - Industrialization without Urbanization: A Study of Attitude Change in Bahir (Folder 548: 16)
    - Sack, Richard, abstract, "Education and Modernization in Tunisia" (Folder 549: 1)
  - Schulhof, Tom, questionnaire (Folder 549: 2)
  - Schuman, Howard, "A Note on the Rapid Rise of Mass Nationalism in East Pakistan" (Folder 549: 3)
  - Shah, Vimal P. (Folder 549: 4)
  - Simmons, John, "Harvard University Research Project in North Africa" (Folder 549: 5)
  - Spencer, Daniel L., "External Military Technological Transfer and Structural Change" (Folder 549: 6)
  - Spencer, Metta, "The Partisan Student" (Folder 549: 7)
  - Stark, S. and Kugel, Y., "Toward an Anthropology of Dogmatism: Maladjustment, Modernization..." (Folder 549: 8)
  - Stump, Jordan, Friesen, "Cross Cultural Considerations in Understanding Vocational Development" (Folder 549: 9)
  - Suzman, Richard, "Personality Correlates of Modernity" (Folder 549: 10)
  - Szalai, A., Comparative Time Budget Study (Folder 549: 11)
  - Taylor, Phillip B., "US Prestige Jolted in Columbia" (Folder 549: 12)
  - Tessler, Mark A., "Cultural Modernity: Evidence from Tunisia" (Folder 549: 13)
  - "Two Thorny Theoretical Tangles" (Folder 549: 14)
  - White, Leslie, "Nations as Socio-Cultural Systems" (Folder 549: 15)
  - Whyte, Martin, Child Rearing Scales, 6/68 (Folder 549: 16)
  - Whyte, Wm. Foote, "The Role of the US Professor in Developing Countries" (Folder 549: 17)
  - Whyte, Wm. Foote, "Social Change and Community Development: A Comparative and Longitudinal Study in Peru" (Folder 549: 18)
  - Young, F.W. and R.C., "Individual Commitment to Industrialization in Rural Mexico" (Folder 549: 19)
  - Zechowski, Z.A., On the "Peripheration of Small Towns in an Industrialized Region" (Folder 549: 20)
  - Zuckerman, Michael, "The Fabrication of Identity in Early America" (Folder 549: 21)
  - Namboodiri, N. K., "The Wife's Work Experience and Child Spacing" (Folder 549: 22)
  - Needler, Martin, "Political Development in Latin America" (Folder 549: 23)
  - Nelson, Joan, "Migrants, Urban Property and Instability in Developing Nations" (Folder 549: 24)
  - Paydarfar, Ali A., "Studies in Iran" (Folder 550: 1)
  - Presser, Stanley, "Survey Respondents as a Source of Measurement Error" (Folder 550: 2)
  - Rogers, E.M., "Diffusion of Innovations in Rural Societies" (Folder 550: 3)
  - Rogers, Everett, "Elements in the Sub-Culture of Traditionalism" (Folder 550: 4)
  - Roos, Leslie L. "Attitude Change and Turkish Modernization" (Folder 550: 5)
  - Rosow, I., Excerpt from "Housing and Social Integration of the Aged" (Folder 550: 6)
  - Rotham, Stanley, peasant and worker questionnaire (Folder 550: 7)
  - Rotter, Julian, "Generalized Expectancies for Internal Versus External Control of Reinforcement" (Folder 550: 8)
  - Goael, Lal, "Political Parties in India" (Folder 550: 9)
  - Landsberger and Hewitt, "A Pilot Study of Participation in Rural Organization and Political Socialization in Mexico" and Henry Landsberger, "The Labor Elite in Latin America: Is It Revolutionary?" (Folder 550: 10)
  - Littunen, Y., "Continuity, Change, and Democratic Values" (Folder 550: 11)
  - McCord, William, questionnaire on values (Folder 550: 12)
  - Meyer, Larry, "In Search of International Modernity", 1974 (Folder 550: 13)
  - Miquel, Andre, "Training and Economic Development" (Folder 550: 14)
  - Miller, Karen, "Social Position, Satisfaction, and Political Tendencies in Chile", 1970 (Folder 550: 15)
  - Miller, S. M., "Poverty in an International Context", (World Congress of Sociology 66) (Folder 550: 16)
  - Montzingo, David, Paper based on project data, January 1970 (Folder 550: 17)
  - Miller, Karen, Summary of Work on Family Modernity, 12/10/1971 (Folder 550: 18)
  - Tumin, questionnaire (English) (Folder 551: 1)
  - Tumin, Spanish questionnaire, "Estudio de Estratificacion y Mobilidad Social" (Folder 551: 2)
  - Perlman, Janice, "The Impact of Urban Experience..." (Brazil report) (Folder 551: 3)
  - Peshkin-Cohen questionnaire (Folder 551: 4)
  - Ramu, G.N., "Studies on Village and Family Life" (Folder 551: 5)
  - Linz, Juan J. "Estudio Sobre la Situacion Social de Espana" (Folder 551: 6)
  - de Miguel, Amando, questionnaire (Folder 551: 7)
  - Fletcher, Philip R., "Educacao Basica E Desenvolvimento Comunitario" (Folder 551: 8)
  - Sic Country Scale codebook, copy II, Vol. I (Folder 551: 9)
  - Morgan, James, questionnaire and bibliography (Folder 552: 1)
  - "Individual Modernity and Agricultural Innovation" (Folder 552: 2)
  - Jacob, Philip E., "Values Measured for Local Leadership" (Folder 552: 3)
  - Jordan, John E., papers and letters (Folder 552: 4-5)
  - Jordan, John, "Guttman Facet Design and Development of Cross-Cultural Attitudes to/Mentally Ret. Persons Scale" (Folder 552: 6)
  - Jordan and Friesen, "Attitudes of Rehabilitation Personnel toward Physically Disabled Persons" (Folder 552: 7)
  - Kahl, Joseph A., "The Measurement of Modernism: A Replication" (Folder 552: 8)
  - Kahl and Goering, "Stable Workers, Black and White" (Folder 552: 9)
  - Katz, Marlene, abstract, "The Effect of Increased Classroom Participation..." (Folder 552: 10)
  - Katz, Marlaine L. "The Effect of Increased Classroom Participation on Lower Class Students? Sense..." (Folder 552: 11)
  - Kaufman and Cole, "Sociological and Social Psychology Research for Community Development" (Folder 552: 12)
  - Kugel, Yerachmiel, abstract, "Modernity Comparison, Moshav and Kibbutz" (Folder 552: 13)
  - Kugel, Y., "Communalism, Individualism and Psychological Modernity: A Comparison of Kibbutz and Moshav..." (Folder 552: 14)
  - Current and Past Project Personnel, Current Project reports, Non-IV project papers, IV reports, OM Scale Users (Folder 552: 15)
  - General project description, questionnaire, index of questions and sampling design (Folder 553: 1)
  - Project publications (Box 553)
    - Book 1 (of 3), reprints 1-9 (Folder 553: 2)
    - Book 2 (of 3), reprints 10-21 (Folder 553: 3)
    - Book 3 (of 3), reprints 22-51 (Folder 553: 4)
  - Multi-Country comparisons (Folder 553: 5)
  - Meyers memos I (Folder 553: 6)
  - Meyer memos II, IV (Folder 554: 1-2)
  - User's manual, (Parts 1-2), Computation Center, Stanford University (Folder 554: 3-4)
  - Field Director's report HUPSCAD, copy 1 (Folder 554: 5)
  - HUPSCAD reports, James H.U. (Folder 555: 1)
  - Wylbur/370, "The Stanford Timesharing System," Reference Manual (Folder 555: 2)
  - Index to alphabetical index, copy 4 (Folder 555: 3)
  - "Ideales, Expectivas, y Aspiraciones," Juan Cesar Garcia, Center for International Affairs (Folder 555: 4)
  - Background Papers, Vol. I, copy 1 (Folder 555: 5)
  - Project Related Papers, Vol. II, copy 1, Parts 1-2 (Folder 556: 1-2)
  - Reprints Project Publications, Parts 1-2 (Folder 556: 3-4)
  - Chile codebook, cards 1-17, copy VIII (Folder 556: 5)
  - Card file for Item and Scale Index (Box 557)
  - Bibliography card file (Box 557)
  - Bibliography card file (contd.) (Box 558)
  - Topical headings index card file through 31 July 1969 (Box 558)
  - Computer printouts of data sets (Box 559)
  - Samples of computer data processing cards (Box 559)
  - "Emergency Relief Fund for Bangladesh" poster (Box 559)